appspotr.com 2019-11-14

# Privacy policy – Appspotr

Appspotr™ takes your privacy seriously. We will not sell, lease, or exchange your personal data to, or otherwise share your personal data with, third parties in ways other than described in this Privacy Policy. Personal data means all information that can help to identify you as a unique person (i.e. name, address, pictures, IP-address etc.) and that are gathered through our digital channels, like this website, mobile applications and/or other future digital interfaces that are linked to this policy. By using Appspotr™ including services available at the Appspotr™.com domains, you are using a service provided by Appspotr AB (“Appspotr”) and we ask you to read our privacy policy carefully to get a clear understanding of how we collect, use, protect or otherwise handle your personal data in accordance with our website. Furthermore, your rights as a data subject are described in this policy.

We take privacy matters and your security very seriously when processing your personal data. If you have any questions you are welcome to contact us. Our contact information can be found under the heading “Contact information”.

The Appspotr™ Service (“the Service”) requires a login to provide you with a personalized account. During our account registration process, we will collect a login name, password, country of domicile and an email address from you. If you register your account through Facebook, we will collect your name. You must provide all of this information in order to obtain an account. After completing our registration form, you will receive a welcome email describing your new Appspotr™ account, and how to access that account. You may, at your option, also store your social media credentials as part of your account with our Service. Our legal grounds for such processing is the fulfilling of the agreement. Collection of such information and processing is necessary for us to fulfill our rights and obligations per the agreement with you (See our Terms of Use).

**Account Subscriptions** If you choose to continue with the Service via a paid account, Appspotr will collect personally identifiable information (the four last digits of your credit card number) and keep this information on file in our secure server in order to provide information about which credit car you are using. This information is only used to verify credit card authenticity, and issue invoices as per your service agreement. If we are unable to process your subscription for a given month, this information, along with your account information, may be used to contact you. Our legal grounds for such processing is the fulfilling of the agreement. Collection of such information and processing is necessary for us to fulfill our rights and obligations per the agreement with you (See our Terms of Use).

**Server Logs** When accessing web pages on the Appspotr™.com domain, Appspotr may log your IP address, access URL, time of access, browser type, and referral URL in order to provide us with internal information regarding site traffic statistics. This information may also be used to identify users who are using the service for spam or other activity that is deemed in conflict with our Terms of Service. This information is used in the aggregate, and is never linked back to any personally identifiable information. Our legal grounds for such processing is our legitimate interests, the processing is necessary to improve our products for our customers and to deter suspicious activity that might be harmful to our services.

**Retention period** of our personal data in our services is until the agreement ceases and 49 months for non-essential data. Payments and payment data requires a longer retention period per the Swedish Bookkeeping Act and can be stored up to 7 years.

Appspotr collects the aforementioned personally identifiable information in order to provide you with a service that allows you to maintain an online presence. Various features in our website management system will, at your discretion, display your name, or adjust the date and time of events based on your locale. The Appspotr™ Dashboard interface will always give you an option before any piece of your personally identifiable information is presented on your website, and situations where information will be published is made clear in various spots in the interface (for example, your name is tied to welcome emails you send out from our system, and notice of this is given to you within the interface for that tool). Appspotr also uses information collected through the Service to send out notifications regarding service related issues (such as maintenance periods, billing problems, account expirations, and other items that may impact service). We do not send contact information unless the matter is deemed urgent, and most communication will occur through your Appspotr™ Dashboard interface. We also may use your information to send you messages regarding new services or other products from Appspotr, but will not share this information with third parties for any marketing purposes. Information collected through our service logs is used only to identify potential cases of abuse and establish statistical information regarding website traffic. This statistical information is not aggregated in such a way that would identify any particular user of the system. Appspotr AB is the sole owner of information collected on <https://www.appspotr.com/>. Your information is never shared, leased or given to any third parties in ways other than disclosed in this Privacy Policy.

If your account is inactive for 49 months it will be deactivated and deleted unless you act to negate such deactivation and deletion. You will be prompted to reactivate your account before we take final action to deactivate and delete your account.

For your app or any module or service that is linked and used in your App, where you get information of App users; you are considered a Data Controller whereas Appspotr is a Data Processor. You are responsible for any data inquiries by your users (“End-user”). Appspotr provides tools for our developed modules, in the case of third parties they must enable such functionality in their service. Appspotr does not guarantee such functionality from third parties.

We store all user information in secure databases protected via a variety of industry-standard access controls. Hashed passwords, SSL encryption, disk-based encryption, firewalls, and other measures are in place that helps us to protect your data. This data is accessed only for the purposes specified in this privacy statement. If you have any questions about security on our website, you can review our hosting FAQ or send us a support request using our support system.

**Changing Information** All information that Appspotr stores related to your account, including any subscription billing information, is accessible through your Appspotr™ Dashboard interface. You may use this interface to adjust your information at any time, and we encourage you to keep this information up to date so that your customer service requests and billing processes operate efficiently.

**Removing Information** To remove your personally identifiable information from our system, submit your account for deactivation. Your personal information will be removed as soon as possible from our system, though your actual login name will remain reserved on our system until re-collection. If you wish to only remove your billing subscription information, cancel your paid account. Both of these removals can be accessed through your Appspotr™ Dashboard interface.

**Service-related Announcements** We will send you service-related announcements on rare occasions when it is necessary to do so. For instance, if our service is temporarily suspended for maintenance, we might send you an email. Generally, you may not opt-out of these communications, which are not promotional in nature. If you do not wish to receive them, you have the option to deactivate your account.

**Other Messages** We may also send you messages from time to time about new features or services that we will offer to our users. You may opt-out of these communications at any time by clicking on the link at the bottom of our communications to you, or by changing your preferences in your profile.

**Customer Service** Upon issuing a customer support request to the Service, we may use your information and email address to contact you regarding your inquiry and share support case information with our support management system provider Zendesk.

**Aggregate Information (non-personally identifiable)** We share aggregated demographic information about our user base with our advertisers. This information does not identify individual users. This information contains statistics related to traffic and the geographic location of our customers. We also may share aggregated user information with third parties who help us to analyze our user base to improve the Service.

We do not link aggregate user data with personally identifiable information.

**Personally Identifiable Information** Appspotr employs third-party service providers (processors) to perform functions on our behalf, such processors are used for the following tasks; icredit card processing, email service providers, analyzing data, providing customer service. These service providers have access to personal information needed to perform their functions, but may not use it for any other purposes.

Other examples of 3rd party services are modules in the Appspotr Marketplace where a 3rd party is the owner or developer of a service/integration etc. If you activate a 3rd party module, information of you and your account details may be sent to this 3rd party developer

In the event of a business transfer or sale by Appspotr, customer information generally is one of the transferred business assets but remains subject to the commitments made in any pre-existing Privacy Policy (unless, of course, you consent otherwise).

We may release account and other personal information when we believe release is appropriate to comply with the law; enforce or apply our Terms of Service; or protect the rights, property, or safety of Appspotr, our users, or others. This includes exchanging information with other companies and organizations for fraud protection and credit risk reduction.

Notwithstanding anything else in this policy, we may work with partners who use mobile SDKs, including the OneSignal Messaging SDK, to passively collect information (collectively, “SDK Information”), which generally helps us deliver personalized notifications. This data may also be used to identify you in a unique manner across other devices or browsers for the purposes of customizing ads or content. Depending on the permissions granted to the application, this information may include personally identifiable information (PII) including your e-mail address. This information may also include precise location (i.e. GPS-level data) or WiFi information, apps you have installed and enabled, and your mobile identifier (e.g., Android Advertising ID).

**Opting-out of OneSignal Push Notifications**

You may in most cases opt out of receiving push notifications by going to your device “Settings” and clicking on “Notifications,” and then changing those settings for some or all of the apps on your device. (Different device configurations, or updates to devices, may affect or change how these settings work.)

**Opting Out of “Cross-App” Advertising on Mobile Devices**

You can opt out of having your mobile advertising identifiers used for certain types of interest-based (also called “cross-app”) mobile behavioral advertising, by accessing the “settings” on your Apple or Android mobile device, as follows: By opening the Google Settings app on your device, selecting Ads, and then selecting the option to opt-out of interest-based ads. (Different device configurations, or updates to devices, may affect or change how these settings work.)

As is true of most websites, we gather certain information automatically and store it in log files. This information includes internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, operating system, date/time stamp, and clickstream data.

We use this information, which does not identify individual users, to analyze trends, to give support, to track specific cases when needed, to administer the site, to track users’ movements around the site and to gather demographic information about our user base as a whole. We do not link this automatically-collected data to personally identifiable information. We base such processing on our legitimate interests to improve our products and store such data for up to 24 months.

This Website contains links to other sites that are not owned or controlled by Appspotr. Please be aware that we, Appspotr, are not responsible for the privacy practices of such other sites. We encourage you to be aware when you leave our site and to read the privacy statements of each and every website that collects personally identifiable information.

This Privacy Policy applies only to information collected by this Website.

We try to keep your personal data within the EU/EEA and most of our own IT-systems are localized accordingly. Providers outside of the EU/EEA are Amazon Web Services who are certified under the EU-US Privacy Shield . During support and maintenance, we might also temporarily need to transfer information outside of the EU/EEA.

All personal data will always be kept to a minimum and relevant to the cause. Regardless where the personal data is transferred, we always take adequate technical and organizational measures to secure that the level of security is the same as within the EU/EEA and therefore maintains an adequate security level, i.e. by using the EU-commission’s standard contractual clauses or companies that are affiliative to the Privacy Shield.

You have the right to request information regarding the personal data that we process of you and have inaccurate information corrected. Keep in mind that we can ask for additional information about you to ensure safe and effective processing of your request and to ensure that information is given to the right person.

You have the right to demand that we remove the personal data we have of you, i.e. if information no longer is needed to achieve the purpose they were collected for or if you no longer wish to receive direct marketing etc. Observe that when deemed necessary we can reject your request, i.e. if the personal data is required for tax- or auditing purposes. If you want to contact us, please see our contact information under “Contact information” below.

You also have the right to request the limitation of processing. In such cases we might not be able to you the Service and therefore might have to assess the situation before making such a decision. However, such a request will most likely result in the inability to use the Service and deletion of your account.

In cases where you have given your consent or if the processing is based on a contractual relationship with you, you have the right to, under certain circumstances, have your data transferred to another personal data controller. This on the other hand requires that the transfer is technologically possible and can be done by automated means.

If you want to know how we process your personal data you can send a written and signed request to us (see “Contact information” below).

In the event Appspotr goes through a business transition, such as a merger, acquisition by another company, or sale of all or a portion of its assets, your personally identifiable information will likely be among the assets transferred. You will be notified via email of any such change in ownership or control of your personal information.

We reserve the right to disclose your personally identifiable information as required by law and when we believe that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights and/or to comply with a judicial proceeding, court order, or legal process served on our Website.

If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will post those changes to this Privacy Policy, the homepage, and other places we deem appropriate so that you are aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances, if any, we disclose it. We will not materially change our policies and practices to make them less protective of customer information collected in the past without informing affected customers.

We reserve the right to modify this Privacy Policy at any time, so please review it frequently. If we make material changes to this Privacy Policy, we will notify you here, by email, or by means of a notice within your Appspotr™ Dashboard interface.

If you have any questions or suggestions regarding our privacy policy, please contact us by using our support system.

**Appspotr is located at:** Skånegatan 29, 412 52 Gothenburg, SWEDEN

All correspondence should be sent to: Appspotr AB, Skånegatan 29, SE-412 52 Gothenburg, SWEDEN,

For general inquiries: [info@appspotr.com](mailto:info@appspotr.com)

For privacy inquiries: [privacy@appspotr.com](mailto:privacy@appspotr.com)

_If your personal data is not processed in accordance with this policy or relevant data protection legislation you have the right to file a complaint to Swedish Data Protection Authority._
